Let us discuss this example.
So, that's something that occurred in the
slides, as the example of using a function
to express an animation.
So, let's first run this and see what
happens. Well, as hypothesized, there is this
triangle which moves to the right
because there is this change of t.
And this happens continuously.
So, there's no discrete sampling here, at
least not visibly, because the animationOf
function somehow, internally makes sure
that this looks nice in the browser.
Okay, how does it do this?
And that was also mentioned, well, essentially,
it will call the scene function on an individual
value.
So, we could also say, well, we could ourselves
call the scene function on different time
stamps, so to speak.
And that's also used later in the list comprehension
example for discrete, separate drawings of
this triangle.
Here, I have to add this drawingOf call.
And then, for example, this would now somehow
draw three time-steps (three snapshots) of
this triangle. So, at the places at the
points where I chose by changing the
values here. Of course, I can also take something
else, like three, and then there will be another
copy somewhere else.
Of course, I shouldn't make a typo.
And then this would work.
Okay.
Also, as seen later, we could… if you have
more than two values, two pictures that you
want to combine, you could also use this
"pictures" function, just to illustrate this here.
And then I can put arbitrarily many pictures.
In this case, calls of this 'scene' function
into this list, and the
output here will be the same.
Okay, so that's by actually combining many
of such calls in a way that we don't need
to explicitly control.
Also, the 'animationOf' function works, then
we don't actually say at which time stamps
we want to see the function.
But the 'animationOf' function does
this for us by using such copies of the
triangle and showing it over time.
Okay, this also provides us with some means
or possibilities of manipulating this. For
example, we could say we want
to make the whole thing quicker.
Yes.
So, let's say you want to have a quicker scene.
And, of course, you could say we do this
by somehow changing this here, right?
Or we could say, well, we don't want to change
the definition of the 'scene' function, because
maybe this is used elsewhere, or at least
is somehow a thing that we don't want
to change because there are
some fixed semantics for us.
But we still want to have somehow a quicker
animation here or a quicker version of the
'scene' function
of this animation. Now, of
course, it's not defined.
So, how can I define it?
Well, of course, I could start, I could say,
well, let me define it exactly as before.
But I don't really want to copy this here.
So, let me actually say the 'quickerScene'
function is exactly the same as the 'scene'
function.
This would work and wouldn't actually
change anything in what we see.
But let me say that actually, I wanted the
'quickerScene' function to take some additional
argument, expressing by how
much things should be faster.
Let me say, I wanted that.
It's another argument here.
And what I want to say here is that, for example,
I want the scene to be quicker by a factor
of five.
Okay, that's what this parameter
is about, this f parameter.
And then it should somehow be
a quicker version of the scene.
Of course, if I simply say it's equal to
scene, that's not what's going to happen.
Let me say, what do I want to be
the case at a given point in time?
Well, if I want the scene to move quicker,
then I should say that, actually, I somehow
speed up the time.
I can do this by multiplying the
factor. I can say, when quickerScene is
called with time 1,
then I actually want to call scene with
time 5, which is what will happen if I give
the 5 argument here.
Okay, what have I obtained by doing this?
I get the same animation, but it's quicker
without actually changing the 'scene' function.
Because I just do function
composition, I define new functions.
And in this case, I defined the 'quickerScene'
function by calling the 'scene' function, but
with some other argument.
Okay, and there are different ways to express
this, but this is the one which is probably
most accessible to you right now.
Okay, and then I can really combine things.
For example, I can say, actually, I want to
run both animations, I want to run the scene
and the quickerScene.
So,
what do I do? Then I have defined a new function?
So, let me say I want to have this new function,
which is the combination of the other two.
It will be an animation, so it
must go from double to picture.
And what I want to do here is I
want to run this combined thing.
Okay, then what should "combined" be? I should
define what it is at a certain point t.
And what do I do there?
Well, what I really want is, it should
be the original scene, combined with my
quickerScene, but of course
at the same point in time.
Okay, now, if I run this, what
should I expect to happen / to see?
Well, I should expect a combination of the
original animation and the faster, the quicker
animation.
Let me do this and check this.
And see, that's exactly what happens.